Andrew August

713-560-8192 | aaugust288@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/andrew-august | ajaugust.com

Summary

Experienced Data Scientist specializing in data-driven modeling for pattern discovery. One year of experience at a geospatial startup focusing on computer vision. Four years of experience at a government R&D lab focusing on machine learning security. Six years of experience in teaching and teaching assistant roles. Currently seeking a new opportunity after team was laid off due to budget cuts.

Tools

Languages: Mostly Python

Libraries: ML frameworks (torch, sklearn, mlflow, etc), geospatial frameworks (gdal, rasterio, geopandas etc),

visualization (matplotlib, plotly, etc)

Collaboration: Atlassian products (Jira, Confluence)

EXPERIENCE

Capella Space Remote

Data Scientist 05/2022 - 05/2023

• Developed analytics products for a mid-sized remote sensing startup company. I was on the analytics team and focused on objects detection modeling and dataset curation.

 Collaborated with the product team to design marketable models and worked with a project manager to establish deadlines and deliverables.

Pacific Northwest National Lab

Seattle, WA

Data Scientist

05/2018 - 05/2022

- Developed ML solutions for projects in science, security, and energy. Example areas include adversarial machine learning, object detection for remote sensing, few shot learning, optical character recognition, hurricane intensity modeling, commercial building energy simulation, and differentiable rendering.
- Implemented novel architectures and training protocols to answer research questions related to ML security, particularly adversarial ML, including attacks such as data poisoning, model manipulation, and black-box.
- Networked to become an ML point-of-contact for researchers outside my immediate group. For example, I advised or contributed to projects in groups such as Coastal Sciences, Nuclear Engineering, and Building Energy.
- Promoted to Data Scientist after 8 months of consistent output and positive feedback as a Research Associate.
- Contributed to workforce development through mentoring interns and junior staff, on-boarding new hires, and conducting interviews.
- Implemented ML solutions from academic papers.

Teaching Experience

Instructor / TA

- University of Tennessee (2015 2017): Teaching assistant for the Machine Learning class. Held office hours, helped students write code and understand lecture material, graded projects & exams.
- Programming for High School Students (Summer 2015): Taught a summer class aimed at exposing high school students to college-level programming material. Lessons included intro to web development, intro to excel programming, and intro to python programming.
- University of New Mexico (2010 2012): Teaching assistant for Physics. Demonstrated physics phenomena, guided undergrads through lab sections, designed new demos, substitute lectured, graded exams & homework.

Internships

Research Intern

- OAK RIDGE NATIONAL LAB (05/2017 08/2017): Worked in the GIS group, trained segmentation models for automated mapping applications using tools such as QGIS, Keras, and GDAL.
- SANDIA NATIONAL LAB (02/2010 08/2010): Developed fluid dynamics simulations in fortran to support algae biofuel research. Verified simulations against physical experiments and developed differential equation models of algae growth.

EDUCATION

University of Tennessee

MS Computer Science

Knoxville, TN 2015 - 2017

University of Hartford

BS Physics (summa cum laude)

Hartford, CT 2006 - 2009

Papers

- Differentiable Parametric Optimization Approach to Power System Load Modeling, NeurIPS, 2021
- Deep Learning Experiments for Tropical Cyclone Intensity Forecasts, Weather and Forecasting, 2021
- Systematic Evaluation of Backdoor Data Poisoning Attacks on Image Classifiers, Computer Vision & Pattern Recognition, 2020
- Koopman approaches to physics-informed machine learning for sea-surface temperature forecasting, arXiv, 2020
- Design optimization for a wearable detector array with directionality estimation, Nuclear Instruments & $Methods\ A,\ 2017$
- Spectroscopic Signatures of Dynamic Biological Processes in Algal Communities, Sandia Report, 2012